Hey friends, I am Surendra. Today we will talk about
how to claim insurance. If
you have car insurance, car
insurance, two-wheeler insurance,
motor insurance, and now your car meets with an
accident, then
how do you claim it? So, I am going to explain the whole process step by step. If you have
n't done it
in the entire video and you haven't subscribed to our channel, please
subscribe to our channel. First of all,
I will tell you that there are
two types of car insurance, one is
first party and the other is third party. If we
say third party insurance, then
your car is not insured in it, it is
only the third party, that is, if
your car meets with an accident the day after, if any
car meets with an
accident with our car, it is
called third party, so its insurance is
mandatory for your company. It is
mandatory to have third party insurance in India, after that
comes first party. We
also call first party insurance, Audi
comprehensive, but along with third party,
you will also have to take insurance for the first party, that is, the car. So, the
premium of Audi is very low and that
of third party is very high, so
coverage in third party  There is more coverage of honey,
here you get big insurance,
so now what will happen in Audi,
in Audi you can claim your car,
so I will tell you how we have to
claim the car, so the
whole video will remain, so first of all
if you have met with an accident with your car, then first of all
you have to take
action to the insurance company, you have
their toll free number, they have an email
ID, you can give them information,
nowadays they have chatbots,
WhatsApp chatbots, there are many
other platforms which are doing claim integration so that
you can directly intimate the claim,
now if you want, you can also report the claim to the garage, if
you take the car to the garage, then the
garage can also report the claim to you, so it would be
better that you
report the claim of your car yourself and give the correct information
as they ask,
when you make the claim, at that time keep the
RC of the car, the policy of the car, your
driving license, the driving license of the person who was driving the car
and keep in front of you whatever
they will ask.
You will have to tell how the accident happened, when it happened,
who was driving the car,
what is their driving license number, you will
not know all these things, someone is injured,
someone is injured in their own car or
someone is injured in a third party, the injury is
death, then you will not know all these things.   The day
after tomorrow you will prepare the statement of the vehicle in the garage,
whatever damage has happened to the vehicle, whatever
expenses are there on the vehicle, an estimate will be made for that,
you will pay that estimate and submit it in writing to the garage, along with
this you will have to fill a claim form,
we also have the insurance claim form of the insurance company, you will have to
fill it and give it to me, you can directly
submit it to the garage, the garage will come to me in the morning, your
claim form, estimate of the vehicle,
copy of your policy, copy of RC,
copy of driving license and KYC, in today's time
KYC is also mandatory like your
Aadhar card and PAN card etc. all these are
mandatory, you have to submit it, so
once we take all these things, Jain and your claim will
not stop, try to report
this vehicle on the cashless account of the company, then
you do
not have to lose all your money, this will
not happen first, the reimbursement process will not happen
because first you have paid for your vehicle
from your pocket and after that the company is
giving you the figures, so this is you  Keep in mind that
you can also call their car repair center and
ask them
where you can find a car repair center there. You
can report your car at Neeraj Garage.
Now the surveyors will come to survey your car, so
you can brief the surveyors about the
accident. You can tell them about the accident. It is
possible that the surveyors do
not understand what you have written on the claim form.
To make your claim easily admissible, you
can also talk to the insurance service directly and
tell them how the
accident happened. They will try to find out how you are claiming for the
accident in one go.
Because if you
file many claims at once, then the insurance company will think that you are
uploading a lot of things to the company.
In such cases, the
company may not accept the claim. The more
fresh the damage is, the more you can claim.
You should mention the actual damage
in the form and that is what you will get. Okay,
now let's come, after the survey is done, they will
give your approval. If you feel that the
approval is not as per your requirement, do you think so?
Whatever panel of mine is repaired,
it should be replaced or replaced.
If you want more coverage,
you should be allowed something in it, then you
can do it in the service, you can keep your point of
survey with it, for that your
grievance point, grievance point, all of them have points,
so like the center has a
mail ID of grievance, there is a
mail ID of customer care, you
can report your issue to them and discuss your service, the best thing would be that
first you will talk to the service,
as if they have given you the roll, after that
your car will start getting made, the car will be made on the
basis of approval, after the car is made,
its survey assessment will be made, that is a good thing,
well let me tell you something,
you can take a copy of the done assessment from the survey and an
assessment will be made for the car, after it is made,
its bill details are made,
what they have allowed, how much deduction was made, everything,
you can take a copy of the assessment, it will be
written in it, you can ask for that copy,
you can also take a copy of the copy of
which part has been deducted and why it has been deducted
And why is this definition put on it,
this thing has come up here, so if you ever have your comment
then you can take a copy of your husband from the survey,
now let's come, the car is now made from castor,
now if this car is on cashless
then there you get
a delivery order from the delivery order,
what is the delivery order,
after the car is made, after
deciding the liability, I will tell Girraj that much
payment will be made to you, mother,
make a bill of ₹100 and after the company's lemon tea assessment of 95 sir,
then 95 will be
paid directly by the company at night,
you can directly take the difference of ₹5,
this is yours, now what is good in it,
if you have a car policy then you have good news, the
company will give you the claim today,
not the car, clothes, underwear, zero depression coverage,
means what is in it, mother, if you have an
item of ₹100, then you will get the entire
item of ₹100,
keep such things in mind, try to
take a zero depth policy only, so in the next, I will take
some videos  I will come and tell you the story about
which coverages you should
take in your vehicle, which are very important in today's date.
You
can save yourself from a huge liability by paying a low premium in that. So,
you must watch the next video as well.
Okay, so right now let me clear
your cashless tax for today. Now
we come to the reimbursement point
where you have made the payment from your pocket.
Where the reimbursement happens, there too the
survey is the same
process as everyone. The same documents will be required
from everyone. In numbering, the
surveyor will come to see the vehicle initially.
When the vehicle is made, he will come to take photographs. And
after the vehicle is made, then there is a
restriction on the vehicle, it is called range.
Finance. What will be the amount changed in the vehicle and will be
placed in front of the vehicle,
its range will be fixed. After that,
this is a process in both cashless plus non-cost settlement and cashless. The
only thing is that
in cashless, you are paying the full payment. You do
not have to pay the full payment.
In needle, for example, the one with ₹100 is
also passing you by.  I have to make the payment,
here in reimbursement you have to make the full
payment of ₹100, that will be
deposited by the insurance company, you will have to give your bank details,
you will give the copy of the cancelled cheque, then the
payment will come in reverse in your account, whatever deductions will be there, like if
he had paid 95 to the garage, then
95 will be given to
you, this is the complete process, if you still have any
doubt in this, you want to know some
story, if you have any claim stuck, if
you have any other doubt, then you can tell me in the comment box.